<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magdalena Bienias</title>
    <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Magdalena Bienias</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency price prediction</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project4/</guid>
      <description>Prediction of prices of selected cryptocurrencies using the ARIMA model. Cryptocurrencies that have been analyzed:  Bitcoin, More will be released soon.  Project Overview ARIMA (Auto Regressive Integrated Moving Average) is a combination of 2 models: AR (Auto Regressive) and MA (Moving Average). It has 3 hyperparameters:
 p (auto regressive lags) d (order of differentiation) q (moving average)   which respectively comes from the AR, I and MA components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telco customer churn modelling</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project3/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of the factors that could have an impact on customer churn from the telecom operator. An attempt to predict which customers may opt out of the telecommunications operator&amp;rsquo;s services.
Project Overview  generated a basic report on the input data frame using pandas_profiling; missing data in the &amp;lsquo;TotalCharges&amp;rsquo; column have been supplemented with the median value in this column; data visualizations were created; data was divided into training data (70%) and testing data (30%); the following machine learning methods were tested: logistic regression, support vector machine, random forest, k-nearest neighbor, decision tree; churn probability for each client was calculated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the National Health Fund data on the occurrence of ischemic stroke</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project2/</guid>
      <description>Data was downloaded from the website dane.gov.pl The National Health Fund has reporting data provided by medical entities. The dataset concerns reimbursed services and medications for patients, some of whom have suffered from ischemic stroke. The collection was prepared in such a way that the data on services and medications come from the period of two years (t, t + 1), while the information on the occurrence of a stroke concerns the period of the next two years (t + 2, t + 3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis and search for the most frequently used words in Donald Trump&#39;s tweets</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/posts/project1/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview  the data has been downloaded from the website www.thetrumparchive.com; the analysis was conducted on tweets published from January 20, 2017 to December 31, 2020; only tweets in English were analyzed; sentiment analysis was carried out using the TextBlob library; the thematic modeling was performed with the Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA).  After retrieving the data, I had to clean it to make it usable for analysis. I made the following changes and created the following variables:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi. My name is Magdalena Bienias. I graduated with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in mathematics at the Cardinal Stefan Wyszyński University in Warsaw. I am currently in the second year of master&amp;rsquo;s studies in big data management at the University of Warsaw. In the future, I want to deal with data analysis professionally. I have carried out my projects so far as part of my studies or as a hobby. I am looking for an internship that would help me develop in this direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description> Have questions or suggestions? Feel free to contact me:
   Platform URL     e-mail: magda199711@gmail.com   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-bienias-313n1a5/?locale=en_US   GitHub: https://github.com/blondeincode    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blondeincode.github.io/portfolio/projects/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment analysis and search for the most frequently used words in Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s tweets in 2017-2020.
Project Overview
 the data has been downloaded from the website www.thetrumparchive.com; the analysis was conducted on tweets published from January 20, 2017 to December 31, 2020; only tweets in English were analyzed; sentiment analysis was carried out using the TextBlob library; the thematic modeling was performed with the Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA).  After retrieving the data, I had to clean it to make it usable for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
